Samuel King

LinkedIn | GitHub

A responsible and motivated Software Engineer, I have a passion for clean and well-tested code. Experience building and maintaining enterprise web applications in the Professional Services and E-commerce space. I am a skilled communicator and team player, comfortable integrating into new teams and working to deliver timely and effective solutions. I drive my own learning and personal development, experimenting with new technologies to expand my skill set.

Relevant Experience

Sainsbury's Tech, Software Engineer (May 2021 - present)

Working in the Shared Services team to replace a legacy monolith with a set of decoupled microservices, serving downstream tech teams.

- · Design and delivery of an event driven microservice architecture, using Kafka for messaging
- Implemented custom libraries to handle eventstore and kafka integrations within NestJS
- Reduced API times from circa 30s to 25ms
- Interacting with business stakeholders to gather information required for the creation of a migration plan
- Lead planning and refinement sessions, ensuring that the team has enough tasks to work on in upcoming sprints
- Present regularly at team knowledge share sessions, advocate for continuous improvement, new technologies, and the use of agile methodologies
- Give technical presentations to other teams (microservice architecture demonstration)
- Support the hiring process, conducting interviews for Node.js positions
- · Assist with onboarding new team members, helping to develop and mentor engineers

Tools and technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, NestJS, GraphQL, Avro, Kafka, Postgres, MongoDB, Gremlin, Neptune, Jest, AWS, Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Docker

Accenture, Software Engineer (October 2019 - May 2021)

- Build e-commerce solution to meet client needs, working full-stack using JavaScript technologies
- Implementation of various full-stack features, building UI components, development and consumption of REST endpoints, third-party integrations
- Sole responsibility for design and implementation of end-to-end performance test solution: writing test scripts, configuration and deployment of test environment, and automation of test runs
- Facilitation of weekly Engineering Guild forum. Delivered regular presentations to guild of 40+ engineers, senior management, and client stakeholders

Tools and technologies: React, Redux, TypeScript, GraphQL, Node.js, Jest, AWS Lambda, Elasticsearch, JMeter, BlazeMeter, Jenkins

Caterpillar, Graduate Engineer (September 2018 - September 2019)

- · Process improvement projects lead, working with internal and external stakeholders
- Responsible for design and development of new and existing hardware

Ricardo, Undergraduate Software Engineer (July 2015 - July 2016)

Delivery of major software features on commercial automotive design application (Java)

Tools and technologies: Java, MATLAB

Side Projects

- Web development blog sk52.github.io a Gatsby blog used as a testing ground for learning new technologies, and documenting the process. For example:
 - o Publishing Private a Private Package to GitHub

Volunteering

Onja, Volunteer Career Counsellor (June 2021 - present)

- A social enterprise in Madagascar that trains capable, low-income youth into frontend developers
- Conducting mock interviews on a weekly basis to prepare students for their first developer roles

Education

Makers Academy (October 2019 - December 2019)

- Intensive 12-week web development course at Makers Academy in London
- Pair programming, team projects, TDD, agile methodologies, OOP

Cardiff University (September 2013 - July 2018)

- MEng, Mechanical Engineering, First Class Honours
- School Prize for Best 3rd Year Project (Development and Application of a Bees Algorithm Optimisation Module)

